Guide to the Montana Power Company Predecessor Company records 1880-1947
Montana Historical Society
- Walter M. Bickford
  - General Correspondence
    - F (correspondents include Fatherless Children of France; H.J. Faust, Ovando; Clara Ferguson, Pony; Firlands Trust Company, Portland, Oregon), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 209 / 6)
    - W. Earl Greenough, Spokane, Washington (re General Exploration Company), 1917, 1920 (Box-folder 209 / 7)
    - G (correspondents include Albert J. Galen, Helena; G.H. Garnett, Victor; Geyser Land Company; Genevieve Gilbert, Portland, Oregon; John Gillie, Butte; Great Western Mines Company of Nevada; J.F. Greenawalt, Helena; H.C. Groff, Victor; C.L. Gruwell, Idaho Falls, Idaho), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 209 / 8)
    - Hall and Patterson, Missoula, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 209 / 9)
    - G.B. Harrington and Company, Spokane, Washington (re mining investment), 1912-1928 (Box-folder 209 / 10)
    - James Alexander Henshall, Tupelo, Mississippi (re fish hatcheries), 1911-1922 (Box-folder 209 / 11)
    - Ha-Hi (correspondents include Walter H. Hanson, Wallace, Idaho; E.A. Hardcastle, Butte; Helen M. Harrignton, Los Angeles; Heilbronner Company; Elmer E. Hershey, Missoula; Dan J. Heyfron, Missoula), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 209 / 12)
    - E. Hofer and Sons (Pacific Coast Manufacturer and Industrial News Bureau), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 209 / 13)
    - Holcomb and Keegin, Washington, D.C., 1911-1912 (Box-folder 209 / 14)
    - Henry C. Hopkins, Butte, 1911-1918 (Box-folder 209 / 15)
    - Edward Horsky, Helena, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 209 / 16)
    - Ho-Hy (correspondents include Bertha Holland, Anaconda; Charles H. Hubbell, Cleveland, Ohio; George W. Hunt, Grandville, Illinois; F.S. Hyde, Oakland, California), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 209 / 17)
    - I (correspondents include State of Illinois; Inter-Mountain Good Roads Association; Interstate Consolidated Telephone Company; Irving Whitehouse Company), 1909-1920 (Box-folder 209 / 18)
    - George Jackman, Seguim, Washington, 1917 (Box-folder 209 / 19)
    - Charles A. Jakways, Ovando, 1911-1918 (Box-folder 209 / 20)
    - Charles F. Juttner (re fishing and politics), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 209 / 21)
    - J (correspondents include Inga Jaten, Butte; Johnson Brothers and Blanchard, Boat Builders), 1911-1920 (Box-folder 209 / 22)
    - J.S. Keerl (re request for pardon and his engineering work while in prison), 1911 (Box-folder 209 / 23)
    - Conrad Kohrs, 1911-1919 (Box-folder 209 / 24)
    - K (correspondents include Otto Kahn, New York; John W. Keener, Washington, D.C.; Thomas J.C. Kenny, Ovando), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 209 / 25)
    - Lee, Higginson and Company, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 210 / 1)
    - Lemhi Union Mining Company, 1912 (Box-folder 210 / 2)
    - John D. Losekamp, Billings, 1909-1913 (Box-folder 210 / 3)
    - L (correspondents include Larabie Brothers, Bankers; Lauzier Wolcott Company, Butte; Lawyers Cooperative Publishing Company; Scott Leavitt, Congressman; William I. Lippincott, Butte; William H. Llewellyn, New York; Floyd J. Logan, auto dealer), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 210 / 4-5)
    - E.P. Mathewson, Toronto, Canada, New York, 1911-1920 (Box-folder 210 / 6)
    - Ma (correspondents include T.H. MacDonald, Kalispell; Sara Mackay, Bickford's daughter; M. Maher, Burke, Idaho; John J. Marquette, Missoula; Dwight N. Mason, Helena; Lee Knowles Maxey, Yakima, Washington), 1910-1927 (Box-folder 210 / 7)
    - Adrian McClaman (Simpson, Thatcher and Bartlett, New York), 1928 (Box-folder 210 / 8)
    - R. Lee McCulloch, Hamilton, 1911-1918 (Box-folder 210 / 9)
    - Mc-Me (correspondents include Ward L. McCafferty, Roscoe, S.D.; McMullen and Wickstead, DeBorgia; Mechanics and Metals National Bank), 1911-1921 (Box-folder 210 / 10)
    - Missoula Chamber of Commerce, 1911-1928 (Box-folder 210 / 11)
    - Missoula City and County, 1909-1928 (Box-folder 210 / 12)
    - Missoula Light and Water Company (S.R. Inch; C.H. Christensen; G.B. McLeod; George R. Brown), 1909-1924 (Box-folder 210 / 13-14)
    - Missoula Mercantile Company (C.H. McLeod; includes Liberty Bond drive), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 210 / 15)
    - Missoula Public Service Company (C.H. Christensen), 1925-1928 (Box-folder 210 / 16)
    - Missoula Rotary Club (includes bylaws and membership list), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 210 / 17)
    - Missoula Street Railway Company (S.R. Inch; George R. Brown), 1909-1917 (Box-folder 210 / 18-19)
    - Missoula Trust and Savings Bank (J.M. Keith), 1909-1927 (Box-folder 210 / 20)
    - M (correspondents include C.R. Middleton, Baudette, Minnesota; William Mills and Son, Fishing Tackle; Missoula Building and Loan Association), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 210 / 21)
    - Montana Attorney General, 1911-1927 (Box-folder 210 / 22)
    - Montana Bureau of Civilian Rehabilitation (includes annual report), 1928 (Box-folder 210 / 23)
    - Montana Fish and Game Commission; Montana Fish Hatchery (C.F. Healea; E.P. Mathewson), 1911-1920 (Box-folder 210 / 24)
    - Montana Governor (Edwin L. Norris; S.V. Stewart; W.R. Allen; J.E. Erickson), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 211 / 1)
    - Montana Industrial Accident Board (A.E. Spriggs; includes political discussions re workers compensation, Non Partisan League etc.), 1916-1919 (Box-folder 211 / 2)
    - Montana Public Service Commission, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 211 / 3)
    - Montana Secretary of State (A.N. Yoder; Thomas M. Swindlehurst; A.M. Alderson; William Powers), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 4)
    - Montana State Land Dept. (C.A. Whipple; F.H. Ray; Sidney Miller), 1911-1920 (Box-folder 211 / 5)
    - Montana State University, Missoula (includes report of library committee, 1928), 1915-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 6)
    - Montana [miscellaneous government agencies], 1911-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 7)
    - Mo (correspondents include Montana Good Roads Congress; Montana Newspaper Association; Charles C. Moore and Company, Engineers; A.T. Morgan, Butte; E.A. Morley, Helena; Moulton Mining Company), 1911-1925 (Box-folder 211 / 8)
    - C.H. Muckler, South Dakota lands, 1911-1920 (Box-folder 211 / 9)
    - Mulroney and Mulroney, Missoula, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 10)
    - William L. Murphy, Missoula, 1911-1917 (Box-folder 211 / 11)
    - William Muth, Helena, 1911-1919 (Box-folder 211 / 12)
    - Mu (correspondents include Muchmore's Real Estate and Investments, Ovando; George V. Mullan, New York), 1911-1920 (Box-folder 211 / 13)
    - Henry L. Myers, Senator, 1912-1919 (Box-folder 211 / 14)
    - T.J. Nerny, Butte, 1911-1918 (Box-folder 211 / 15)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Company, 1911-1926 (Box-folder 211 / 16)
    - N (correspondents include National Economic League; Navy League of the United States; New York State; New York War Camp Community Service; Dona B. Nicholson, Paris, Illinois; Joseph D. Nowell, Anaconda), 1910-1920 (Box-folder 211 / 17)
    - O (correspondents include W.A. O'Neill, Missoula; State of Oregon; O.B.S. Orr Realty Company, Missoula), 1909-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 18)
    - Pa-Pe (correspondents include Pacific National Life Assurance Company; Earle B. Patten, Mining Engineer), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 19)
    - James C. Phillips (personal), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 211 / 20)
    - Ph-Py (correspondents include W.B. Pickrell, Spokane, Washington; Frank Pierce, Washington D.C.; C.W. Pomeroy, Kalispell; Portland Railway Light and Power Company; Potomac Telephone Company; E.C. Potter, Los Angeles; Powell County; Eva Powell, Dewey; Francis F. Powell, Stevensville; Charles N. Pray, Congressman; John E. Price and Company, Investment Securities; Henry C. Prudhomme, Portland, Oregon; J. C. Pyle, Butte), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 21)
    - L.L. Quigley, Butte, 1928 (Box-folder 211 / 22)
    - William Q. Ranft (includes Iron Mountain Tunnel Company), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 211 / 23)
    - Ravalli County, 1911-1928 (Box-folder 211 / 24)
    - Real Republican State Committee (re Non Partisan League), 1920 (Box-folder 211 / 25)
    - William Leonard Renick, Butte, 1911 (Box-folder 211 / 26)
    - James M. Rhoades, Real Estate, Missoula, 1908-1917 (Box-folder 211 / 27-30)
    - Charles F. Ruggles, Butte, 1911 (Box-folder 212 / 1)
    - R (correspondents include Raymond and Whitcomb Company, Tours and Cruises; J.E. Reardon, Hamilton; Record Title Company, Billings; H.C. Rice, Portland, Oregon; J.W. Rickman, Victor; George W. Robbie, Butte; Mary A. Robbins, Milltown; Robert F. Rose, Helena; J.H. Rowe, Butte), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 212 / 2)
    - Salmon Lake Club, 1917-1928 (Box-folder 212 / 3)
    - Eueidas K. Scott (re Navy Recruiting Station, Portland), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 212 / 4)
    - Sa-Se (correspondents include Sanders County; Samuel E. Schwartz, Butte; Security Bridge Company), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 5)
    - Alex C. Shaw (re Hyde case; lieu land selection, etc.), 1913-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 6-7)
    - George F. Shelton, Butte, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 212 / 8)
    - Sh-Sm (correspondents include Peter Sherlock, Burke, Idaho; Clara B. Shuart, New York; Silver Cable Mining Company, Missoula; C.A. Smith, Potomac), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 9)
    - Carroll Smith, Anaconda (re fishing), 1912-1918 (Box-folder 212 / 10)
    - Lewis A. Smith, Butte, 1912 (Box-folder 212 / 11)
    - Snow Storm Mining Company; Snow Storm Mines Consolidated, 1911, 1919 (Box-folder 212 / 12)
    - Mrs. J.K. Stadler, Helmville (re fishing trips), 1911-1912 (Box-folder 212 / 13)
    - W.J. Stephens, Seattle, 1912-1918 (Box-folder 212 / 14)
    - Stewart and Welch, Spokane, 1911 (Box-folder 212 / 15)
    - D. Gay Stivers, Butte (see also: Anaconda Copper Mining Company; Butte Anglers Club), 1912-1913 (Box-folder 212 / 16)
    - So-Sw (correspondents include Stilson Brothers Real Estate, Los Angeles; Andrew Stinger, Ronan; Alex D. Stoddard, Philipsburg; Stoddard and Price, Missoula Insurance and Real Estate Agency; Art Stover, Potomac; John Strasser, Butte; Superior Rod and Gun Club), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 17)
    - John L. Templeman, Butte (see also Clark Legal Dept.), 1912-1921 (Box-folder 212 / 18)
    - T (correspondents include Richard J. Taggart, Washington D.C.; H.S. Thane, Missoula; Thomas Rod Company, Bangor, Maine; Tolan and Gaines, Missoula; O.W. Tong, Helena; Truscott Boat Manufacturing Company), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 19)
    - United States Bureau of Fisheries, 1911-1917 (Box-folder 212 / 20)
    - United States Forest Service, 1917-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 21)
    - United States Internal Revenue Service, 1911-1927 (Box-folder 212 / 22)
    - United States Land Office (includes General Land Office; Surveyor General), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 212 / 23)
    - United States Senate, 1911-1917 (Box-folder 212 / 24)
    - United States [miscellaneous agencies], 1911-1920 (Box-folder 212 / 25)
    - U-V (correspondents include Union Bank and Trust Company, Helena; United States National Bank, Deer Lodge; Ursuline Convent, St. Ignatius; Utah Lithographing Company), 1909-1917 (Box-folder 212 / 26)
    - Thomas J. Walsh, 1912-1920 (Box-folder 213 / 1)
    - Charles S. Warren, Butte, 1912-1921 (Box-folder 213 / 2)
    - Washington (State) Secretary of State, 1909-1919 (Box-folder 213 / 3)
    - Western Empire Insurance Company, 1909-1917 (Box-folder 213 / 4)
    - Western Lumber Company (C.H. Richardson, R.J. Brown; includes lists of lands), 1910-1928 (Box-folder 213 / 5-9)
    - Western Lumber Company (re F.A. Hyde forest lieu land selection; correspondents include Jeremiah Collins, A.C. Shaw, U.S. General Land Office), 1901-1922 (Box-folder 213 / 10-11)
    - Western Montana Flouring Company (C.H. Richardson), 1910-1917 (Box-folder 213 / 12)
    - Wa-We (correspondents include C.S. Wagner, Hamilton; Wallace National Bank; Washington State Sportsmen's Association; P. Welch, Spokane, Washington; Eugene Wessinger, Lothrop; Western Sportsman), 1911-1920 (Box-folder 213 / 13)
    - R.G. Wiggenhorn, Red Lodge, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 213 / 14)
    - Dr. T.C. Witherspoon, Murray Hospital, Butte, 1911-1917 (Box-folder 213 / 15)
    - Wh-Wo (correspondents include D.J. Whaley, Stevensville; Winston Brothers Company, Minneapolis; Marguerite Wright Wohltman, Brooklyn, N.Y.; T.S. Woodford, McAllister; Charles F. Word, Helena), 1911-1920 (Box-folder 213 / 16)
    - Y-Z, unidentified (correspondents include Chelnessa Young, Potosi Springs; Edythe Zeigler, Missoula), 1911-1918 (Box-folder 213 / 17)
  - Case Files
    - John J. Buckley Estate, 1917 (Box-folder 213 / 18)
    - C.H. Christensen vs. E.C. Likes and Marjorie Likes; C.H. Christensen vs. G.L Walkup, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 213 / 19)
    - William A. Clark vs. Walter Cooper, et al. (includes correspondence with H.A. Bollinger, W.A. Clark, W.C. Siderfin, W.S. Hartman, and others; and court papers), 1913-1917 (Box-folder 213 / 20-24)
    - C.O. Gruwell indebtedness to William A. Clark, 1911 (Box-folder 213 / 25)
    - Edwin A. Harris Estate, 1927 (Box-folder 213 / 26)
    - Lauzier, Wolcott and Company bankruptcy, 1925 (Box-folder 213 / 27)
    - Clarence A. Maloney vs. William A. Clark Jr. and William A. Clark III (re vicious dog), 1927 (Box-folder 213 / 28)
    - William E. Pinkney vs. Bridger Improvement Company et al. (defendants include W.A. Clark; Walter M. Bickford; A.H. Wethey), 1918 (Box-folder 213 / 29)
  - Financial Records
    - Bills and receipts: fishing supplies, boats, etc., 1911-1913 (Box-folder 214 / 1)
    - Bills and receipts: legal supplies, legal filings, law books, etc., 1911-1913 (Box-folder 214 / 2)
    - Bills and receipts: miscellaneous, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 214 / 3)
    - Checkstubs, 1920 (Box-folder 214 / 4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deed to land in Oregon from Grace and William Muth, 1913 (Box-folder 214 / 5)
  - Printed Material
    - "The Revolutionary IWW: the Greatest Menace in the United States Today", undated (Box-folder 214 / 6)
  - Subject Files
    - Forest lieu land selections by F.A. Hyde and Western Land Company (includes correspondence with C.W. Holcomb and W.C. Keegan; United States General Land Office; Jeremiah Collins; Collins Land Company; John M. Evans; Elmer E. Hershey; A.C. Shaw; lists of lands) [see also individual correspondents], 1900-1922 (Box-folder 214 / 7-10)
    - Geyser Land Company, 1909-1918 (Box-folder 214 / 11)
    - Issuance of bonds (correspondents include William A. Clark; A.H. Wethey), 1909-1911 (Box-folder 214 / 12)
    - Life insurance cancellation by Clark Realty Company, 1928 (Box-folder 214 / 13)
    - South Missoula lots: abstracts of title and deeds, 1876-1917 (Box-folder 214 / 14-15)
    - South Missoula lots: account with James M. Rhoades, 1908-1911 (Box-folder 215 / 1)
    - South Missoula lots: lists and memoranda, undated (Box-folder 215 / 2)
    - South Missoula lots: maps [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], undated (Oversize-folder 5)
    - Spotted Bear proposed road (correspondents include William A. Clark, Jr.; William I. Lippincott, Butte; letters to Congressmen and Senators), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 215 / 3)
    - Stock certificates (William A. Clark, et al.), 1910-1911 (Box-folder 215 / 4)
    - Western Lumber Company / Big Blackfoot Milling Company negotiations, 1913 (Box-folder 215 / 5)
    - Wyandotte and Soldiers' Scrip (includes correspondence of William A. Clark and W.E. Moses), 1904-1914 (Box-folder 215 / 6)
  - Writings
    - Untitled (re constitution), 1923 (Box-folder 215 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Court cases settled and pending, 1910, 1914, 1916 (Box-folder 215 / 8)
    - Lists of corporations owned by William A. Clark with incorporation dates, officers, and stockholders, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 215 / 9)
    - Stock certificates owned by Walter M. Bickford (includes Argenta Mining Company, Geyser Land Company, Lemhi-Union Company, Maxville Mines Company, Stoney Creek Coal Company), 1912-1920 (Box-folder 215 / 10)
  - Clippings
    - Speech at dedication of John Mullan statue, undated (Box-folder 215 / 11)
- James M. Brown
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous: A-W, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 215 / 12)
  - Financial Records
    - Bills and receipts, 1917 (Box-folder 215 / 13)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 215 / 14)
- William L. Murphy
  - General Correspondence
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company Lumber Dept., 1921 (Box-folder 216 / 1)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte and New York (W.C. Siderfin), 1914, 1922 (Box-folder 216 / 2)
    - A-W, 1912-1916 (Box-folder 216 / 3)
  - Case Files
    - W.J. Babington, Missoula County Clerk and Recorder vs. C.A. Stillinger, 1913 (Box-folder 216 / 4)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway vs. John W. Stewart and Patrick Welch, 1915 (Box-folder 216 / 5)
    - Ella Falligan vs. School District #1, Ravalli County, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 216 / 6)
    - George Hammrstad vs. Bates and Rogers Construction Company (re injury), 1911 (Box-folder 216 / 7)
    - Thomas G. Hathaway Estate, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 216 / 8)
    - Francis G. Higgins Estate, 1916 (Box-folder 216 / 9)
    - B.T. Lavelle vs. W.P. Mills (re medical malpractice), 1913-1916 (Box-folder 216 / 10)
    - City of Missoula vs. Kate H. McCormick (re Isis Theater), 1913 (Box-folder 216 / 11)
    - Missoula County vs. County Fair Board (re liquor sales), 1914 (Box-folder 216 / 12)
    - Lillian Peterson vs. John Lynch et al. (re irrigation ditch), 1915 (Box-folder 216 / 13)
    - Adolph Thur vs. Everett D. Peck (re medical malpractice), 1911-1912 (Box-folder 216 / 14)
    - William S. Weaver guardianship, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 216 / 15)
    - John Woodson vs. First National Bank of Missoula, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 216 / 16)